Daniel Nwaobi Ifechukwude

WEB DEVELOPER, DESIGNER AND TECHNICAL SUPPORT ENGINEER

dannychukz15@gmail.com

in @nwaobidaniel

@CrazyChickenDev

+2348022273025

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm an open-source/blockchain enthusiast, technical support engineer, computer engineer, web developer and designer. As a technical Support Specialist with over 5 years of experience, I have a proven track record of providing IT support and troubleshooting for hardware, software, and systems. I possess a strong understanding of IT infrastructure and networking concepts and have experience collaborating with technical and non-technical stakeholders to deliver successful projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

REGIONAL DAO TECH COMMUNITY MANAGER @HARMONYONE

DEC 2021 - JUNE 2022 (TENURE)

- I worked with my fellow community managers to build the official Harmony Regional DAO website which is translated into 4 local languages.
- Created every design asset for the Harmony NaijaDAO Worked with my team to draft the initial proposal with a funding of \$50,000 from Harmony Designed marketing, branding and media assets Technical Training organisation and onboarding of future blockchain builders Offline advocacy and outreach Strategy and brand growth.
- Designed and actively led strategies promoting community growth.
- Onboarded new members onto the DAO Initiated rapid education drive and helpful conversations around blockchain, Defi and NFTs, A poll in the community showed that 25% of people got their first cryptocurrency (\$ONE) or digital asset via the DAO outreaches.
- Facilitated the DAO's first Meet-up in Nigeria on February 19 2022, with over 100 people in attendance and facilitated the second meetup in Lagos Nigeria which was held on April 2, 2022.
- Built and designed websites and mobile apps during my community manager tenure.
- Experienced working in a fast-paced environment and managing a high volume of community inquiries or requests.

IT SUPPORT ENGINEER AND DEVELOPER @ WISPER TELECOMMUNICATION

OCT 2021 - JAN 2022

(CONTRACT)

- Provided technical support to over 500 users and employees across multiple departments.
- Monitored and maintained communications IT infrastructure, including servers, switches, and firewalls.
- Conducted regular backups and disaster recovery testing.
- Developed and maintained programming/interface standards.
- Collaborated with other IT teams to deliver successful projects.

TECH. SUPPORT ENGINEER AND DEVELOPER @ MUZZLABS

MAY 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2021(FULL TIME)

- Built and designed websites and mobile apps during the initial internship span.
- Wrote modern, performant, maintainable code for a diverse array of client and internal projects.
- Responded to over 1000 customer inquiries and complaints via phone, email, and live chat.
- Developed and maintained documentation for technical processes and procedures.
- Communicated with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, producers, and clients on a daily basis.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to resolve complex customer issues.
- · Managed customer accounts and provided guidance on products and services.
- Set up and configured new hardware and software, including operating systems and productivity software.
- Participated in training sessions to improve product knowledge and customer support skills.
- Resolved customer issues in a timely and efficient manner, achieving a customer satisfaction rating of 95%.
- · Mentored new team members on customer support best practices and company policies.

CYBER-SECURITY INTERN @ UNITES

SEPT 2020 - NOV 2020 (INTERNSHIP)

- Gained simulated experiences in the field of cybersecurity.
- Took up specialization courses in Computer Architecture, Software Engineering and Embedded Systems to broaden my skill set and took up electives in "Cyber Security".
- Manually tested networks, routers, systems and websites in various browsers and mobile devices to ensure cross-browser compatibility, responsiveness and vulnerabilities.
- Built projects related to cybersecurity such as keyloggers and password list generators during the internship.

- Built a strong technical community on my campus by organising events, hackathons, workshops, meetups, etc.
- Help created a community where students can comfortably share their ideas and improve their tech and soft skills.
- Developed and maintained code for event websites primarily using HTML, CSS, Sass and JavaScript.
- · Interfaced with community individuals and students on a daily basis providing technological expertise
- Developed and maintained community documentation

EDUCATION HISTORY

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering (B.Eng.)

July 2016 - 2022

University of Benin, Benin City, Nigeria.

HARD SKILLS

- Video Editing (Adobe Premiere Pro, Wondershare Filmora)
- Design (Canva, Figma, Illustrator and Photoshop)
- Programming and Website Development (HTML&CSS, JavaScript, Node.Js, WordPress, React, Gatsby.Js, RESTful APIs, Git)
- Communications (Slack)
- Documentation (MS Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Notion, Google Doc/Slide/sheet, Trello)
- Operating Systems: Windows, MacOS, Linux
- Virtualization: VMware
- Customer support software: Zendesk, Salesforce, Intercom

SOFT SKILLS

- Communication Skills
- Organization
- Presentation
- · Problem Solving
- Conflict Resolution
- Problem Solving
- · Critical Thinking

INTERESTS

- Cryptocurrency
- Blockchain
- Startups
- Programming
- Design
- FinTech
- · Digital Marketing
- SAAS
- Video Games

CERTIFICATION S & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Winner of the "30-day Microsoft Cloud Skills Challenge" Designing and Implementing an Azure Al Solution (June 2020) issued by Microsoft
- First Place WINNER Team "TEAM ARTI" at the "Microsoft Build Cloud Skills Challenge" (June 2020) issued by Microsoft
- GitHub Campus Expert for the University of Benin (2020-2022)
- SEPLAT JV 2020 Scholarship Winner for Students
- "Introduction to Cybersecurity Certification" issued by Cisco Networking Academy
- "ICSI | Cyber-Security Essentials" issued by ICSI, UK (International CyberSecurity Institute)
- "ICSI | Certified Network Security Specialist (CNSS)" issued by ICSI, UK (International CyberSecurity Institute)
- "Cyber Security Foundation Professional Certificate- CSFPC™" issued by CertiProf
- "Networking Academy Learn-A-Thon 2021" issued by Cisco
- "Lifelong Learning" issued by CertiProf
- "Virtual Graduate Internship Program (Cyber Security Operation)" issued by UNITeS Cisco Networking Academy
- Remote Work and Virtual Collaboration Professional Certificate RWVCPC issued by CertiProf